Guide to the Jack and Rebecca Matlock Papers, 1930s-2017 RL.11082
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Subject, Organization, and Name Files, 1946-2010s
  - Subject Files: Topics and Places, 1940s-2000s; 4
    - The Nationalist (newspaper), 1967-1968 (Box 114)
      Scattered issues, including copies of special issue Revolution Day supplement; Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. Collected by JM.
    - NATO expansion, 1990s (Box 81)
      Clippings, reports
    - Ngurumo (newspaper), 1967 June (Box 114)
      Scattered issues, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. Collected by JM.
    - Nuclear weapons/nuclear power, 1980s-2000s (Box 81)
      Reports, clippings, research on capabilities re: power plants, weapons, etc. in USSR and NIS
    - Opinion surveys, 1991-2000s (Box 82)
      Largely of Russian public, also an American Foreign Policy survey
    - Orenburg (Russia), 1992 (Box 82)
      Traveler brochure
    - Perestroika, 1991, 2005 (Box 82)
      Pamphlets
    - Photography, 1950s (Box 82)
    - Pre-Kievan Russia (St. Petersburg), 1976 (Box 82)
      Lecture notes by Voznosensky
    - Pravda (newspaper), 1989 (Box 114)
      Scattered issues of Moscow newspaper collected by JM.
    - Reagan-Gorbachev meetings in Geneva, 1985 Nov. (Box 82)
      Memoranda of Conversations (memcons), notes by JM (created later as part of research)
    - Reagan Library research by JM, 1990s-2010s; 4 folders (Box 82)
      FOIA requests, declassified 1980s documents re: JM, Reagan, others. Photocopies from Reagan Library collected by JM.
    - Refugees/Palestine to "Abu Hussein", 2008 (Box 82)
      Letter from Palestinian refugee re: Israel aggression directed to Obama
    - Rhodesia/Zimbabwe, 1960s (Box 82)
      Air Rhodesia flight routes
    - Russia (general), 1990s; 2 folders (Box 82)
      Administration/officials lists, clippings, reports
    - Russia: investments, economy, business ventures, 1990s-2000s; 2 folders (Box 82)
      Reports, plans, clippings, assessments re: stability of Russian economy
    - Russian Judeaism, 1990s (Box 82)
      Magazine
    - Russian language programs, 1950s (Box 82)
    - Russian leaders/politicians, 1992-2000s (Box 82)
      Clippings, coverage
    - Russian literature/authors, 1930s-1980s (Box 82)
      Research and clippings
    - Russian mining/geology/natural resources, 1950s-1990s (Box 83)
      Soviet-era notes and 1990s reports
    - Russian museums/art, 1980s-2000s (Box 83)
      Printed materials/tourism brochures
    - Russian press/newspapers, 1990s (Box 83)
      Circulation lists, reports, etc.
    - The Samachar (newspaper), 1967 (Box 114)
      Excerpts and assorted issues; Zanzibar-Tanzania. Collected by JM.
    - Slovak Republic constitution, 1992 (Box 83)
    - South Africa magazines, 1963, 1970 (Box 83)
    - South African newspaper clippings, 1970; 2 folders (Box 83)
      Assorted titles and topics, many referencing cricket and apartheid, collected by JM
    - South Ossetia, Georgia, 1992 (Box 83)
    - Soviet-era politics and legal documents, 1980s-1991 (Box 83)
      Re: elections, laws, etc. in Russia and USSR
    - Soviet-era government and leaders, 1980s-1991 (Box 83)
      Reference tools, clippings, etc.
    - Soviet Observer newspaper, 1988 (Box 83)
      English newspaper with coverage of Gorbachev becoming USSR President and Sakharov's visit to US
    - Soviet plays collected by JM, 1970s; 3 folders (Box 83)
      Russian-language plays, photocopied and collected by JM (perhaps for dissertation research)
    - Soviet successor states/Newly Independent States (NIS)/republics, 1990s; 2 folders (Box 83)
      Research, articles, reference tools for the region
    - Soviet Union history (general), 1944-2000s; 2 folders (Box 84)
      Printed materials, clippings, reference tools, reports
    - Spaso House, 1990s (Box 84)
    - The Standard (newspaper), 1967 (Box 114)
      Excerpts and assorted issues from Dar es Salaam (Tanzania) collected by JM
    - Strategic Defense Initiative, 1980s-1990s (Box 84)
      Research and collected information re: 1980s efforts; reports, articles
    - Tajikstan, 1992 (Box 84)
    - Tatarstan, 1992 (Box 84)
    - Teatral'naia Zhizn' (magazine), 1988 (Box 115)
      Four issues collected by JM.
    - Uhuru (newspaper), 1967 (Box 114)
      Assorted issues from Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. Collected by JM.
    - Ukombozi (newspaper), 1967 (Box 114)
      Assorted issues from Zanzibar, Tanzania; collected by JM
    - Ukraine, 1990s-2000s; 2 folders (Box 84)
      Post-Soviet clippings and reports/coverage of conflict
    - Uzbekistan, 1992, 1994 (Box 84)
      Clippings, research on authoritarianism
    - United Nations, 1950s-2000s (Box 84)
      Clippings, reports on UN initiatives
  - Organizations/Professional Service/Businesses, 1987-2010s; 5
    This subseries contains files grouped by organization, largely relating to Jack Matlock's service or consultancy work and including both non-profits as well as business ventures undertaken by him or his family following his retirement from the Foreign Service. Files contain correspondence, proposals and project plans, contracts, reports, event plans, and research. Notable are the range of organizations and companies exploring business ventures in Russia, Ukraine, and Eastern Europe following the collapse of the Soviet Union; Jack Matlock explored many of these opportunities himself and also served as a consultant or resource for other ventures. This series documents the Matlocks' work with Ethnic American Broadcasting Company, later renamed Russian-American Broadcasting Company, as well as their later work with SkyView and other satellite and media companies. There are also significant materials from the US-Kazahkstan Business Council and the Matlocks' Russian clothing company, Red Well. Other organizations which Matlock was actively involved with include the Atlantic Council and the Council for Foreign Relations. Of note is the files on the Chautauqua Conference, which overlaps with Jack and Rebecca Matlock's participation in Chautauqua in the 1980s during their years of foreign service. There is also overlap between these files and the chronologically arranged Correspondence subseries in the Personal Files series.
    - ABB Combustion Engineering/Nuclear Power, 1992-1994; 4 folders (Box 84)
      Proposals, invoices, correspondence, and meeting minutes re: ABB (Asea Brown Boveri) and Russian and Ukranian officials/representatives re: power plants and nuclear weapons de-enrichment programs. JM and David Matlock were consultants for ABB (based in Winchestor, Conn.)
    - AGIO Oil and Gas Corporation, 1995 (Box 84)
      Info sheet
    - American Academy of Diplomacy, 1990s (Box 84)
      Membership correspondence and newsletters
    - American Bar Association: Central and East European Law Initiative (CEELI), 1992 (Box 84)
      Info packets
    - American Committee on US-CIS Relations, 1992 (Box 84)
      Report on American business involvement in former Soviet Union
    - American Foreign Policy Council, 1996-2000s; 2 folders (Box 84)
      Moscow visit and other correspondence/agendas from JM's work on Russian-American Working Group
    - American Friends of Georgia, 1995-2003 (Box 84)
      Reports, newsletters, correspondence from JM's service on the board
    - AIS (American Immigration Service, Inc.), 1996-1999; 2 folders (Box 84)
      Correspondence, visa information kits, insurance and legal documentation, and other materials from JM's service on the AIS board.
    - American Philosophical Society, 1997-1998 (Box 85)
      Correspondence and newsletters
    - American-Russian Investment Forum, 1999 (Box 85)
      Advisory board materials
    - American-Soviet Cooperative Exchange (ASCE), 1991 (Box 85)
      Re: Ryzhkov hosting
    - Appeal of Conscience Foundation, 1999 (Box 85)
      Materials re: Duma elections observers, Russia
    - Ark Communications Institute, 1986-1988 (Box 85)
      Newsletters
    - Aspen Institute, Berlin, 1999 (Box 85)
      New Transatlantic agenda
    - Association for the Study of Nationalities / Ian Bremmer project, 1996-1997 (Box 85)
      Correspondence, notes, collected reports re: nationalism. Some overlap with Event.
    - Association of Independent Economists of Slovakia, 1992 (Box 85)
    - Atlantic Council, 1992-2000s; 7 folders (Box 85)
      Assorted files from JM's participation in different Atlantic Council working groups and delegation visits, including: NIS Steering Committee Advisory Board; Working Group on NIS Energy Policy; US-Japan Energy Dialogue; US-Japan-Russia-Ukraine Energy Policy working group.
    - Atlantik-Brucke e.V., 2004, 2008 (Box 85)
    - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1991-2003 (Box 86)
      Correspondence, contact lists, other reports/programming for JM's role in International Peace and Security program
    - Carnegie Foundation: Carnegie Moscow Center, 1998 (Box 86)
      JM's work for an external assessment; final report and trip materials, April 1998
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1996-2000; 2 folders (Box 86)
      Reports, agendas, and other correspondence re: proposals and projects. Include's JM's work for Working Group on US-Russian Relations.
    - Center for Civil Society International, 1993 (Box 86)
      Materials re: newly independent states
    - The Century Foundation, 2009; 2 folders (Box 86)
      Reports; materials re: Russia Working Group meeting 2, New York
    - Chautauqua Conference, 1987-1996; 9 folders (Box 86)
      Materials from RM and JM's partipation in Chautauqua (1987, 1989, 1990-1991, 1996), as well as correspondence, mailings, and clippings about Chautauqua programming.
    - Chilewich Group, 1994 (Box 86)
      Re: Kazakhstan investments
    - Cold War Hot Culture, 2000 (Box 86)
      Folder about the International Festival of Russian Art and Culture
    - Cold War International History Project, 1993, 2002 (Box 86)
      Working papers 6, 37, 38
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1993-2009; 4 folders (Box 86)
      Assorted correspondence, draft reports, papers, and other materials from JM's active role as roundtable participant and his work on the Task Force on US Nuclear Weapons Policy, the working group on US Policy Towards Russia, and the Independent Task Force on US Nuclear Weapons Posture.
    - Dickstein, Shapiro, and Morin, 1993 (Box 87)
      JM consultancy
    - Ditchley Foundation, 1993-1994 (Box 87)
      Chairmen directions, other logistical information
    - Don Pepito Imports LLC, 2005-2006 (Box 87)
      Finances and research for Matlock business
    - Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, 1998-2000 (Box 87)
      Report, correspondence for JM work on advisory board
    - End of the Cold War Forum, 2011 (Box 87)
      Website notes, correspondence
    - Ethnic-American Broadcasting Company/Russian-American Broadcasting Company, 1992-1998; 8 folders (Box 87)
      Legal contracts, business plans, correspondence, research, and notes from JM's work on the board of RABC, which later renamed to EABC.
    - Fifi Oscard Agency, 1990s (Box 87)
      Contracts and correspondence; additional correspondence in Correspondence subseries.
    - Ford Foundation, 1992-1993, 2001 (Box 87)
      Correspondence and information re: workshop series on foreign policy
    - Foundation for children with disabilities in Russia, 2000 (Box 87)
      Materials/correspondence for unnamed foundation, led by Th. Kouwenaar
    - Freedom House: Free Enterprise Initiative, 1994 (Box 87)
      Background materials for JM as advisor
    - Fund for Democracy and Development, 1992-1994; 2 folders (Box 87)
      Background papers, correspondence with FUND advisory committee
    - FSU Energy/Cambridge Energy Research Associates, 1996-1997 (Box 88)
      Overviews, information sheets
    - Global Security Institute, 2007 (Box 88)
      Literature, briefs
    - Gorbachev Foundation, 1990s-2000s (Box 88)
      Correspondence, clippings, reports
    - Greensboro High School, 1990s (Box 88)
      Correspondence, newsletters, packet
    - Grumman Corporation, 1993 (Box 88)
      Nuclear waste proposal
    - Harriman Institute, 1990s (Box 88)
      Printed materials, including lectures and reports
    - Human Rights Watch, 1997-1999; 2 folders (Box 88)
      Reports and agendas from steering committee
    - Institute for the Study of Diplomacy, 1995-1999; 2 folders (Box 88)
      Work on board of directors, based at Georgetown University. Includes reports, agendas, correspondence.
    - International Committee for Economic Reform and Cooperation, 1992-1994 (Box 88)
      Correspondence, reports, etc.
    - International Foundation for Free Press of Russia, 1993 (Box 88)
      Faxes to JM requesting his participation
    - International Foundation for the Survival and Development of Humanity, 1991 (Box 88)
      Report: The Parliament's Responsibility for Economic Development
    - International Research and Exchanges Board (IREX), 1990s; 4 folders (Box 88)
      Memoranda, annual reports, project proposals, contact information and other printed materials; includes JM's board meetings materials
    - Internews, 1992 (Box 89)
    - Ir Amim for an Equitable and Stable Jerusalem, 2008-2009 (Box 89)
    - Johns Hopkins: SAIS, 1993 (Box 89)
      Advisory council briefing book
    - Kennan Institute, 1990s; 5 folders (Box 89)
      Reports, working papers, correspondence, fellowships/grants programs, other administrative materials from JM's work with the institute. Some overlap with Academia Series.
    - Khromatografist ecological center (Ukraine), 1993? (Box 89)
      Correspondence/solicitation materials for minerals/ore/raw materials
    - KUB Association, Perm, Russia, 1993 (Box 89)
      Business promotion pamphlet
    - Mid-America Committee, 1988 (Box 89)
      Moscow visit for trade mission, memoranda
    - Mohan Enterprises, 1994 (Box 89)
      Correspondence, information re: Siberia oil/gas
    - Moscow Amateur Dramatic Society, 1977 (Box 89)
      Program
    - Moscow Lottery Corporation, 1996 (Box 89)
    - Multicultural Omnibus Consulting Team (MOCT), 1990s (Box 89)
      Market research information sheet
    - Museum of Television and Radio, 1995 (Box 89)
      Foreign Affairs advisory committee work
    - National Committee on American Foreign Policy, 1995-2000s (Box 89)
    - National Humanities Alliance, 1998 (Box 89)
      Meeting agendas, materials
    - Port. ru, 1999-2000 (Box 89)
      JM participation on advisory board
    - Project on Ethnic Relations, 1999-2000 (Box 89)
    - Projectavision, Inc., 1994-1996 (Box 89)
      Information about Projectavision and its products/equipment, correspondence
    - Red Well / Black Earth, 1998-2001; 3 folders (Box 89)
      Business plans, finances, correspondence between JM and Hugh and David Matlock re: management of Red Well, a Russian children's clothing company
    - Religions Board of Muslims of Russia's Central European Region (DUMCER), 1998 (Box 89)
      Information booklet
    - Religion in Communist Dominated Areas, 1989-1990 (Box 89)
      reports, publications
    - Rural Development Institute, 1997 (Box 90)
      Prospects for Peasant Farming in Russia report
    - Russia-World Trade Organization forum, 2002-2003 (Box 90)
      Correspondence, printouts from JM's work as moderator of this electronic forum
    - Russia State Library for Foreign Literature, 1993-1996 (Box 90)
      International Board of Trustees communications
    - Russian-American Commission on Foreign Investment, 1993 (Box 90)
      Communications, agendas for members
    - Salzburg Seminar, 1994; 4 folders (Box 90)
      Materials from planning course "American Foreign Policy: Clinton and Beyond," as well as board of directors meetings and communications
    - Seminar on Post-Communist States, Societies, and Economies; Columbia University, 1993-1994 (Box 90)
      Papers, minutes
    - SkyView World Media, 1999-2001; 6 folders (Box 90)
      Correspondence, legal documents and actions, insurance, reports, claims, and other materials from JM's work on board of directors
    - Soviet Interview Project, University of Illinois, 1985-1986 (Box 91)
      Oral histories and working papers
    - Third Millennium Russia Fund, 1998 (Box 91)
      Draft prosectus, communications
    - Transnational Vladimir Solvyov Society, 1994 (Box 91)
      Resource packet
    - TRIUMPH (Russian Independent Fund for Encouraging the Best Achievements in Literature and the Arts), undated (Box 91)
      Pamphlet
    - University of California Berkeley, 1990s; 2 folders (Box 91)
      JM board of advisors work for the Institute of Management, Innovation, and Organization, and for UC Berkeley-St. Petersburg University School of Management program
    - Ukraine Enterprise Corporation, 1995 (Box 91)
      Information packet and private breakfast meeting materials
    - US-Kazakhstan Business Council, 1994; 2 folders (Box 91)
      Printed materials, correspondence, reports, prospectuses, other items about investment opportunities and potential for Kazakhstan
    - US Secretary of Energy: Russia Task Force, 2000 (Box 91)
      Advisory board report "A Report Card on the Dept. of Energy's Nonproliferation Programs with Russia"
    - Washington Institute of Foreign Affairs, 1998, 2001 (Box 91)
      Membership books
    - Women's National Democratic Club, 1996 Mar. (Box 91)
      Audience question cards from JM program
    - World Affairs Council, 1998 (Box 91)
      Speakers program with JM speaking about NATO
    - World Anticriminal and Antiterrorist Forum, 2001 (Box 91)
      Brochures
    - World Policy Institute, 2002 (Box 91)
      Russian liberalism report
  - Name Files, 1950s-2010s; 7
    This subseries contains clippings and writings by others, filed by author or subject's name. Matlock collected a number of these files in the years immediately following his retirement, largely relating to his own research interests as he worked on his book. Also of note are the number of proofs and reports he collected by other foreign policy scholars; he maintained an active correspondence with many of them. The Gorbachev files include photographs of Matlock with Gorbachev dating from the 1990s.
    - Afanasyev, Yuri, 1992 Mar. 8 (Box 100)
      news article about power and society
    - Aganbegyan, Abel, 1988 (Box 100)
      copy of report on Perestroika
    - Aitmanov, Chingiz, 1991 Sep. 11 (Box 100)
      news clippings
    - Aksyuchits, Viktor, undated (Box 100)
    - Aliev, Geydar, 1992 May 17-24 (Box 100)
    - Arbatov, Alexei, undated (Box 100)
      comments on JM detente chapter
    - Åslund, Anders, 1993-2005 (Box 100)
      drafts of articles, correspondence
    - Aspin, Les, 1993 Jun. 24 (Box 100)
      draft of remarks
    - Axinn, Donald, 1977-1987 (Box 100)
      CV, bio, news clippings
    - Baburin, S., 1992 May 2 (Box 100)
    - Bakatin, Vadim, 1992 Aug. 16 (Box 100)
    - Balzer, Marjorie Mandelstam, 1996 (Box 100)
      draft of article
    - Becker, Kurt, undated (Box 100)
      draft of article (incl. German)
    - Bergoltsev, Leonid, 2005-2006 (Box 100)
      correspondence, bio
    - Bernard, Richard P., 1992 Jan. 13 (Box 100)
      memo
    - Billington, James H., 1990-1999 (Box 100)
    - Blanton, Thomas, 1989-1997 (Box 100)
    - Bocharov, Mikhail, 1992 (Box 100)
    - Bohlen, Charles, 1960 (Box 100)
      correspondence
    - Bokser, Vladimir, 1991 Oct. 23 (Box 100)
    - Bolkhovitinov, N.N., 1980, 1998 (Box 100)
    - Boren, David L., 1994 (Box 100)
    - Bremmer, Ian, 1995-1998 (Box 100)
      copies of reports
    - Brent, Jonathan, undated (Box 100)
      draft of "In Stalin's Head"
    - Brown, Archie, 2004 (Box 100)
      essay drafts
    - Bunich, Pavel, 1992 May (Box 100)
      news clippings (incl. Russian)
    - Burbulis, Gennady, 1992 (Box 100)
    - Byerly, John, 2008 Aug. 22 (Box 100)
      copy of interview
    - Centeno, Miguel Angel, 1994-1997 (Box 100)
      CV, articles
    - Chebrikov, Viktor, 1989 Sep. 19 (Box 100)
    - Chernenko, Konstantin, 1987-1991 (Box 100)
      interview transcripts
    - Chubais, Anatoly, 1992 (Box 100)
    - Clemens, Walter, 1998 (Box 100)
      article, correspondence
    - Cloud, Daniel, 1996 Apr. 1 (Box 100)
      speech
    - Combs Jr., Richard E., 2004-2005 (Box 100)
      correspondence, incomplete book draft
    - Daniels, Robert V., 1988 Jul. 11 (Box 100)
      article
    - Dante, undated (Box 100)
      JM notes on
    - Davies, Richard Townsend, 1983-2005 (Box 100)
      news clippings, draft articles
    - Dean, Jonathan, 1996 (Box 100)
    - Desai, Padma, 2004-2005 (Box 100)
      including JM interview transcript
    - Dilworth, J. Richardson, 1997 (Box 100)
      memorial program
    - Dobrynin, Anatoly, 1995 (Box 100)
      review of book by
    - Edgerton, William, 1988 (Box 100)
      articles
    - Ekedahl, Carolyn, 1997 (Box 100)
      proof of "The Wars of Eduard Shevernadze"
    - Elchibey, Abulfaiz, 1992 Sep. 22 (Box 100)
    - Engerman, David, 2009 (Box 100)
      proof of "Know Your Enemy: The rise and fall of America's Soviet experts"
    - Falin, Valentin, 1988 Oct. 20 (Box 101)
    - Fedorov, Boris, 1992 May 24 (Box 101)
    - Feeney, Mark, 2000 Oct. 26 (Box 101)
    - Filatov, Sergei, 1992 Mar. 11 (Box 101)
    - Fishman, David, 2011 (Box 101)
      draft proposal on innovation from the joint Russian-U.S. Legal Initiative
    - Frolov, Ivan, undated (Box 101)
      bio
    - Gaidar, Yegor, 1992 (Box 101)
      clippings (incl. Russian)
    - Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1988 Sep. 24 (Box 101)
      speech draft
    - Gamsakhurdia, Zviad, 1992 May 27 (Box 101)
    - Gardner, Hall, 2016 Sep. 16-17 (Box 101)
    - Gershchenko, Viktor, 1992 Aug. 15 (Box 101)
      clipping, bio (incl. Russian)
    - Goethe, 1949 (Box 101)
      JM notes, scholarly article
    - Gogol, Nikolai, undated (Box 101)
    - Golembrovsky, Igor, 1992 Mar. 8 (Box 101)
    - Golikov, Vyacheslav, 1992 Jun. 21 (Box 101)
    - Gorbachev, Mikhail, 1988-1992; 2 folders (Box 101)
      includes photographs of JM with Gorbachev and of Gorbachev at Reagan's funeral (signed by Gorbachev)
    - Goss, Bernard, 1984-2000 (Box 101)
      draft articles (?)
    - Grachev, Andrei, 1995 (Box 101)
      draft of book "Final Days"
    - Grachev, Pavel, 1992 Sep. 28 (Box 101)
    - Grimsted, Patricia Kennedy, 1997 Sep. 1 (Box 101)
    - Gromyko, Andrei, 1988 Oct. 27 (Box 101)
    - Gruliow, Leo, undated (Box 101)
      obituary statement
    - Guroff, Gregory, 1981 Sep. 29 (Box 101)
      report
    - Gusman, Yuli, 1991 Apr. 22 (Box 101)
      CV
    - Henrikson, Alan, 1999 Apr.-Jun. (Box 101)
    - Kennan, George, 1956-2007 (Box 101)
    - Khamidullin, Filzya, undated (Box 101)
    - Khasbulatov, Ruslan, 1992 (Box 101)
    - Khizh, Georgy, 1992 May 26 (Box 101)
    - Khudonazarov, Dovlat, 1991 Nov. 22 (Box 101)
    - Kochetkov, Georgy, 2000 Apr. 12-Jun. 13 (Box 101)
      interview
    - Kokoshin, Andrei, 1992 Apr. (Box 101)
    - Konychev, Sergei, undated (Box 101)
    - Korniyenko, Georgi, 1975-2006 (Box 101)
      clippings, bio
    - Korotich, Vitaly, 1989-1992; 3 folders (Box 101)
      draft articles, draft of memoir "Zerkalo" (Mirror) (incl. Russian)
    - Kotkin, Stephen, undated (Box 101)
    - Koval, Yuri, undated (Box 101)
      short stories (incl. Russian)
    - Kozyrev, Andrei, 1991-1992 (Box 101)
    - Kravchuk, Leonid, 1991-1992 (Box 101)
    - Kudryavtseva, Tatyana, 2006 (Box 101)
      draft of memoir "A Life's Surprises" (incl. Russian), JM comments
    - Kulmatov, Renat, undated (Box 101)
    - Larrabee, F. Stephen, 1997 (Box 102)
    - Laqueur, Walter, 1992 (Box 102)
      JM comment on Laqueur
    - Lebed, Alexander, 1996 (Box 102)
      clippings and JM notes
    - Lee, Gary, 1986 Mar. 21 (Box 102)
    - Lefebvre, Vladimir, 1983 (Box 102)
      reviews of book "Algebra of Conscience"
    - Lehrman, Edgar, 1982 (Box 102)
      article (?)